# TRISTAN LANGFORD

London | 07526 938 661 | tristan-langford.com | tristanlangford@hotmail.com

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I'm a Full Stack developer, looking for opportunities to continue challenging myself, building applications that will challenge the current technologies and benefit consumers.

Following a 5-year client-facing career in the healthcare sector, I wanted to do a job that I not only enjoyed but would make a difference. Inspired by the recent focus on technology in the healthcare sector, in early 2020 I found what I had been looking for in software development.

I have recently graduated from Makers Academy (London's leading programming bootcamp), learning best practice, tools and methodologies

## **PROJECTS**

Project/GitHub	Details	Tech
Invimcible	Group project. A top-down platformer game to learn Vim commands.	Express, React, Node, Redux
Garmin - Score Tracker	A Garmin ConnectIQ App for tracking the score in 5 a-side football. Change and store team name and timer settings.	Monkey-C
Acebook	Group project. Emulating the functionality of Facebook, using Ruby-on-Rails.	Ruby, Ruby-on-Rails, JavaScript
News Summary	A single-page web app, using AJAX to consume the Guardian API, using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS.	Vanilla JS, HTML, CSS

## TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Languages/Frameworks – JavaScript, Node.js, React, C#, .Net, Monkey-C, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS Testing Frameworks – Jest, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Jasmine, RSpec, XUnit Concepts/Tools – TDD/BDD, Object-oriented design, Pair programming, Continuous Integration & Deployment

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Makers Academy**

May 2020 - August 2020

#### Student

A 16-week intensive programming bootcamp. (Remote due to COVID-19 lockdown)

Primarily self-led training, encouraging students to discover/develop their own solutions, in pairs or teams. Makers champion Agile/XP methodologies and practices, such as pair programming, TDD and OOD.

## Collaborative Procurement Partnership - (Tower 4 provider for NHS Supply Chain)

Jan 2019 – May 2020

#### Category Manager – Orthopaedics

Supporting the delivery of the Future Operating Model within the NHS, through managing the relationships and contract Management with NHS Trusts in the East of England.

**Stakeholder management** with Heads of Procurement and key suppliers, to deliver cost savings for the NHS through the management of a national framework (Total Orthopaedic Solutions Framework)

**Spend Analysis**, reviewing current supplier pricing offers and comparing them to the framework. Negotiating with trusts and suppliers to deliver the best saving possible while ensuring clinical quality

**Delivering change:** Quickly identified areas of weakness within the organisation and introduced processes to remove these weaknesses. Includes Supplier Relationship Management, Account Management Plan, Future Work Plan Model

SCANDIT. OCT 2018 – Jan 2019

## Sales Development Representative – UK, Nordics & Benelux

Computer vision technology company. Handle sales outreach for UK, Nordics & Benelux.

### OrthoD Group

AUG 2015 – OCT 2018

**UK Commercial Manager** 

Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

Hired by leading medical products business in an analytical role and quickly progressed to commercial manager role with P&L accountability, maximising profit and service delivery for primary accounts, with leadership of tenders for new and existing business, working across the NHS and Department of Health.

**Influenced commercial strategy;** collaborated with CEO and CFO to improve pricing, negotiation and account retention, as well as the introduction of new product ranges that offered substantial profit gains.

**Coached Sales Agent to meet first-year target,** growing to over-performance of £98K; set an ambitious but achievable objective, then provided one-to-one support, absorbing useful feedback on products and market.

Created persuasive marketing tools that clarified USPs with high impact distributor incentive scheme.

Presented agile problem resolution and completed ad hoc process improvement projects:

- ✓ Enhanced client satisfaction by replacing a key product, working closely with the client to define requirements.
- ✓ Resolved manufacturing backorder problems; fixed root cause and improved ongoing efficiency through closer alignment of sales forecast to manufacturer production.
- ✔ Prevented account loss by heading project that offered a key change in product sterilisation technique.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.A. (Hons), Economics, Politics & International Relations, 2:1, Oxford Brookes University, 2015

#### **HOBBIES**

**Dulwich Hamlet** - On a Saturday can be found standing in the "rabble" supporting Dulwich Hamlet FC **Cricket** - Regularly play for one of the worst cricket teams in London (formerly officially the worst)